<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>start on itsy.sh</title>
    <link>https://itsy.sh/</link>
    <description>itsy.sh (start)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 14:07:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://itsy.sh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello itsy.sh</title>
      <link>https://itsy.sh/blog/hello-itsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 14:07:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsy.sh/blog/hello-itsy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago i got quite inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://tinyprojects.dev/&#34;&gt;tinyprojects.dev&lt;/a&gt;. Not so much in the
purpose of the site and his quest to create tiny projects. But rather doing something and not just thinking about it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-background&#34;&gt;Some background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the co-founder and CTO of &lt;a href=&#34;https://modularfinance.se?l=en&#34;&gt;modularfinance.se&lt;/a&gt;, modfin, a B2B FinTech firm based in Stockholm that build, run and sell saas applications. For many reasons I&amp;rsquo;m a &lt;em&gt;build-and-run-it-your-self-kind-of-guy&lt;/em&gt; which has led me to build a few different things over the years, sometimes outside the scope for what we do as a company. Tooling and services that helps out in the day to day work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;idea&#34;&gt;Idea&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a move during the last decade to move and outsource things, transactional emails, monitoring, on-call schedules and so on. While there is nothing inherently wrong with this I find it quite frustrating at times. Products trying so solve every kind of problem, adding and charging for feathers that is quite outside the scope with a expensive subscription models and so on&amp;hellip; Eg. pagerduty.com, All I need is to have an on call schedual, and a phone call being made once a post-hook is received. For this they charge $39/month/user which seems quite ridicules if we don&amp;rsquo;t want nor need &amp;ldquo;Super Duper AI Event Intelligence and Analytics&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my plan is simply to open source some of our internal tools and services and build small services and tools that fill the basic need and are easily composed under the bitsy name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Itsy Bitsy services and tools that does one thing well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>