<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on itsy.sh</title>
    <link>https://itsy.sh/blog/</link>
    <description>itsy.sh (Blog)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 08:47:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://itsy.sh/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pingr - Monitor the health and status of your services</title>
      <link>https://itsy.sh/blog/pingr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 08:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsy.sh/blog/pingr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With more and more of our time being spent online, we have been increasingly spoiled by low response times and
constant uptime. To fulfil internal and external demands at businesses, it is therefore more important than ever
to ensure that your services perform as expected. Here to help you, I present Pingr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-pingrhttpsgithubcomitsy-shpingr&#34;&gt;What is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/itsy-sh/pingr&#34;&gt;Pingr&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pingr is designed to monitor your services and let you know whenever a service is behaving unexpectedly. It does
so by poll and push tests. Pingr will poll your services using various different methods such as HTTP-requests or
an ordinary ping. By polling every X seconds, Pingr will monitor your response times as well as any error related
behaviour. Push tests expect your service to poll Pingr using HTTP atleast every Y seconds. In case an error is
thrown, Pingr can contact you via email or post-hook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://modularfinance.se/?l=en&#34;&gt;Modular Finance&lt;/a&gt; we use Pingr in conjunction with
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/itsy-sh/callr&#34;&gt;Callr&lt;/a&gt;. Callr let’s you call someone whenever a post request is received.
This means that Pingr can email you when minor errors occur and call you, through Callr, whenever some urgent
error occurs etc. Being a firm that has multiple services deployed, the Pingr and Callr combo, solves the issues of
manually monitoring the health of all these services and let’s you sleep, or not, through an entire night, knowing
that your services are behaving as they should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;test-methods&#34;&gt;Test methods&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poll methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prometheus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TCP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLS/SSL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Push methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prometheus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/itsy-sh/pingr&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello itsy.sh</title>
      <link>https://itsy.sh/blog/hello-itsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 14:07:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsy.sh/blog/hello-itsy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago i got quite inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://tinyprojects.dev/&#34;&gt;tinyprojects.dev&lt;/a&gt;. Not so much in the
purpose of the site and his quest to create tiny projects. But rather doing something and not just thinking about it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-background&#34;&gt;Some background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the co-founder and CTO of &lt;a href=&#34;https://modularfinance.se?l=en&#34;&gt;modularfinance.se&lt;/a&gt;, modfin, a B2B FinTech firm based in Stockholm that build, run and sell saas applications. For many reasons I&amp;rsquo;m a &lt;em&gt;build-and-run-it-your-self-kind-of-guy&lt;/em&gt; which has led me to build a few different things over the years, sometimes outside the scope for what we do as a company. Tooling and services that helps out in the day to day work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;idea&#34;&gt;Idea&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a move during the last decade to move and outsource things, transactional emails, monitoring, on-call schedules and so on. While there is nothing inherently wrong with this I find it quite frustrating at times. Products trying so solve every kind of problem, adding and charging for feathers that is quite outside the scope with a expensive subscription models and so on&amp;hellip; Eg. pagerduty.com, All I need is to have an on call schedual, and a phone call being made once a post-hook is received. For this they charge $39/month/user which seems quite ridicules if we don&amp;rsquo;t want nor need &amp;ldquo;Super Duper AI Event Intelligence and Analytics&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my plan is simply to open source some of our internal tools and services and build small services and tools that fill the basic need and are easily composed under the bitsy name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Itsy Bitsy services and tools that does one thing well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>